看见他时 不要害怕 好吗?
try not to be scared when you see him,okay?
妈妈 我见过他病的样子
Mom,I've seen him sick.
我不害怕
I'm not scared.
这次不一样
This time's different.
他化疗和放疗的量都加大了...
The doctors gave himan extra course of radiati and chemo--
我知道
I know.
你知道我们多么以你为荣 对吧?
And you understand how proud we are of you,right?
手套 口罩
Gloves, mask.
matty.
Matty
你说想在动手术前见见你的哥哥
You said you wanted to see your brother before the procedure.
我知道我看起来像个外星人
I know I look like an alien,
但我保证不会吃掉你的脑袋
but I promise not to eat your brain.
这一切结束之后 你会回来和我玩吗?
When this is done, will you be able to play out back with me?
我会击中所有你抛进好球区的球
I'll rip anything you put near the strike zone.
我们去抽骨髓 让你的哥哥休息一会儿
let your brother rest up while we take some of your marrow.
你不需要呆在隔离室里
You don't need to be in an isolation room,
但我特地把你安排到了你哥哥隔壁房间
but I pulled some strings so you'd be next door to your brother.
我会错过多少比赛?
How many games will I miss?
你只需在这里呆一个晚上
Well,you only have to be here overnight,
但你要好好休息一段时间
but you do have to take it easy for a little bit.
- 我已经错过了两场,- Matty
- I already missed two.,- Matty.
我了解 没关系的
I know.It's okay.
肯定拖后退了
Must've been a drag.
只是要确认你没有受到任何感染
We just had to make sure you weren't exposed to any bugs.
你健康的骨髓,才能治愈你哥哥的白血病...
Because your healthy bone marrow is what's gonna cure your brother's leukemia--
他打喷嚏了
he sneezed.
也许只是过敏
Maybe it's just an allergy.
过敏可不会伴有脾脏肿大和发烧
Not with an enlarged spleen and a fever.
他得了任何一种感染
he's got one of 10,000 possible infections.
那怕只是普通感冒
Even if it's just the common cold,
那样移植也会杀了他哥哥
I do the transplant,he kills his brother.
我们还有多久?
How long do we have?
放射治疗破坏了他的免疫系统
radiation obliterated his immune system.
就算在无菌室里
Even in a clean room,he's only got.
他也只剩下四五天了
four,maybe five days left.
我们不可能很快找到办法的
no way we can solve this that fast.
得去再找一个捐献者
You need to find another donor.
他们是黑人
they're african-american.
几乎不可能再找到完全匹配的了
It makes it nearly impossible to find a full match.
说得对
Tell me about it.
连我的黑手下都找不到了
I can't even find the one I've got working for me.
Foreman去哪儿了?
Where's foreman?
医死患者唤醒你唱诗班男孩的本性
Nothing like a dead patient to send you back to your choir boy roots.
你肯定不能相信
You're not gonna believe what happened.
Wilson刚刚和你一样 治死个孩子
Wilson just killed a kid the same way you did.
他还没有死
He's not dead.
五天转瞬即过
Five days are gonna fly by.
他辐射那孩子时 没有考虑周全
He didn't look both ways before he nuked.
你和你想象中的朋友聊完了吗?
You done talking to your imaginary friend?
因为我想你也该做本职工作了
'Cause I thought maybe you could do your job.
我该对捐骨髓的弟弟使用广谱抗生素
We should start the donor brother on broad spectrum antibiotics.
好主意 如果只想救兄弟其中一人的话
Great idea,if you're looking to save exactly one kid.
广谱抗生素要一个星期才能见效
Broad spec will take at least a week to work.
得用窄谱抗生素
We need narrow spec.
Hector几岁了?
How old is hector?
病人的名字叫Matty 他哥哥叫Nick
our patient's name is matty.His brother's nick.
Hector是我的狗
Hector's my dog.
他大概17岁了
He's about 17.
17岁?
17?
那相当于
That's like.
人类年龄的119岁
119 in human years.
他怎么还活着?
Why is he still alive?
讨论Wilson的狗花20秒 得从五天里减去
five days minus 20 seconds talking about wilson's dog.
得开始做测试
We need to start testing.
粪便采样检查寄生虫 抗体检测...
Stool samples for parasites,antibody tests--
血检否定了所有常见的猜测
blood panel was negative for all the usual suspects.
那是因为感染实在太轻
That's 'cause the infection is too small.
现在检查 犹如草垛寻针
We start testing now,it's like looking for a needle in a haystack.
我们抽血 只能捞上茅草
We draw blood,odds are we're just gonna come up with hay.
得多丢几根针进去
We need to grow more needles.
好吧 也许得说得更明白一点
Okay,that probably needs further explanation.
让捐骨髓那孩子病再重些
We make the donor kid sicker.
让他受冻 让他淋湿 破坏他的免疫系统
We freeze him,we soak him,break down his immune system.
这样就能找到那根针,针眼大到骆驼能穿过
Suddenly we're looking at some needle a camel can pass through the eye of.
那样做可能会使感染散布他全身
Making him sicker risks spreading the infection all throughout his body.
没错 那又怎样?
True,but who cares?
只要知道是什么感染 就可以针对治疗了
Once we know what the infection is,we'll know exactly how to treat it.
只要他不死 就没问题
As long as he isn't dead yet,we're cool.
我们应该按常规手段来办...
We should do what we normally do--
去那孩子家 寻找感染源
go to the kid's house,check for sources of infection.
浪费时间
Waste of time.
你认为感染在房子里
You think it's in the house.
我肯定它在患者身体里
I know it's in the patient.
总比故意让他病得更重安全
Safer than intentionally making the kid sicker.
好 去吧
Fine.Go.
那你们具体打算让Matty病多重?
so exactly how sickare you gonna make matty?
可能得很重
he could get quite ill.
对谁这感觉肯定都不好受 但这是...
This certainly won't be a pleasant experience for anyone,but it's our on--
有没有不带伞时碰到下雨?
ever get caught in the rain without an umbrella?
就是这意思 签字吧
That's all we're talking about here,sign the form.
这比那个要复杂一些
it's a little more complicated than that.
还会做白细胞去除术
We'll also be doing leukopheresis.
通过机器把Matty血中的白细胞过滤出来
We run matty's blood through a machine that filters outhis white blood cells.
但如果没有白细胞 他怎么能及时恢复?
But without his white cells,how can he get better in time?
一旦有诊断结果 立刻把白细胞输回去
We'll pump the white blood cells back as soon as we have a diagnosis.
那样就可以治疗感染 不耽误移植
Then we should be able to cure the infection in timeto do the transplant.
但你们不能保证?
But you can't guarantee?
我们不是通用汽车
we're not gm.
不能召回 不能打折
No recalls,no rebates.
还有问题吗 当你们儿子的生命在消逝
Any more questions while your son's life slips away?
你真觉得我们该这么做?
You really thinkwe should do this?
是的
yes.
抱歉
Sorry.
你的病人 你来说
You patient.You tell them.
这是你的家人
This is your family.
得你来做出决定
It needs to be your decision.
你唯一该说的是"是的 我同意"
all you had to do was say,"yes,I do."
谁都知道你这辈子常常说这句话
God knows that's a phrase you've used often enoughin your life.
每次都是个错误
It was a mistake every time.
消停一下吧 他们同意了
Give it a break.They said yes.
对你来说不够好
That's not enough for you.
你得让他们心甘情愿地同意
You need them to feel good about saying yes.
我花几个月 甚至几年来治疗病人,而不是像你 几个礼拜就好
I treat patients for months,maybe years,not weeks like you.
我比你高
I'm taller.
如果他们不信任我 我就没法工作
If they don't trust me,I can't do my job.
信任的唯一好处就是让你可以操纵他们
The only value of that trustis you can manipulate them.
你应该写问候卡片
You should write greeting cards.
不该给父母做出错误决定的机会
Giving parents the chance to make a bad choice was a bad choice.
至少是他们自己的选择
At least it would've been their choice.
他们会在儿子葬礼上后悔
One they'd regret at their son's funeral.
厨房和厕所一尘不染
Kitchen and bathrooms were immaculate.
不管是什么病 肯定不是从这里得的
Whatever the kid's got,he didn't get here.
不 不管是什么病
No,whatever the kid got,
只能说不是从厨房或厕所得的
he didn't get from the kitchen or the bathroom.
没有人清理过秋千
Nobody cleans swing sets.
是啊
Yeah.
他们儿子10岁了 从6岁开始就没再用过
Because their kid's ten and hasn't used it since he was six.
很显然你觉得这时间花得不值
You obviously think your time could be better spent.
你为什么还来?
Why'd you come along?
对上周发生的事情我很难过
I feel bad about what happened last week.
我能缓过劲来
I'm handling it.
她家里人会起诉吗?
You think the family's gonna sue?
她只有祖父母 而且关系不亲
she only had her grandparents and they weren't close.
那就好
Well,that's good.
我是指对你而言
For you,I mean.
如果打官司了 你更不容易从中解脱
A lawsuit makes it even harder to put behind you.
你从你的困扰中解脱了?
You put yours behind you?
没有
No.
我今天早上醒来的时候 我...
When I woke up this morning I,
我都不记得入院时 她穿着什么衣服
I couldn't remember what she was wearing when I admitted her.
记忆会减退的
Memories fade.
一星期前我害死她,却记不得她穿着什么颜色的上衣
I killed her a week ago and I can't remember what color top she was wearing.
醒来时没有想着她 我会开心
I was grateful when I could wake up not thinking about her.
我和你不一样
I'm not like you.
你的患者死了,是因为当时你因父亲的死讯分心
Your patient died because you were distracted over the death of your dad.
我是思考后 作出的决定
I made a calculated decision.
你的做法像个正常人
You acted like a human being.
我的做法像是
I acted like.
house.
House
这泥里可能有白霉属或者类圆线虫属
It could be mucor or strongyloides in this dirt.
肺部没有症状
No pulmonary symptoms.
他安顿得很好 呼吸正常
He's setting well,breathing easily.
妈妈 我好冷
Mom,I'm freezing.
还得多久...
How long.do I have to--
Matty 我们在你家后院发现一个机井
matty,we found an old water pump in your backyard.
你有喝里面的水吗?
You ever drink from it?
有 超级恶心的
Yeah,it was gross.
我们得检查分歧杆菌 钩端螺旋体病
We gotta test for mycobacteria,leptospirosis.
你什么时候喝的水?
When did you drink the water?
去年夏天?
Last summer?
你确定?
You sure?
你确定玩热的时候没有去喝一小口?
You haven't even taken a sip to cool off?
那真的超级恶心
It was really gross.
我的肩膀难受
My shoulder's bugging me.
有问题吗?
Does that matter?
有可能
It could.
你弄伤过?
Did you do anything to hurt it?
就是那天抛球
Just threw the ball around the other day.
练了几个小时
For a couple of hours.
可能只是肌肉酸痛
It's probably just a muscle ache.
如果恶化 告诉我们
Let us know if it gets worse.
有点别的疼痛 不是我得病的原因吧?
So soreness and stuff,th's not 'cause I'm sick?
还有什么让你不舒服?
Is something else bugging you?
算是吧
Sort of.
他有阴囊急症
he has acute scrotum.
很可爱 请继续
Adorable.Please,
我以为你品格高尚
I thought you were dignified.
拜托 我不该开那个玩笑吗?
Come on,how am I not supposed to make that joke?
生殖腺肿大 至少有一点好处
The best thing about big honkin' gonads--,well,one of the best things--
它只会由少数几种感染导致
is there's only a few infections that could cause it.
做个尿分析
Do urinalysis
以及培养大肠杆菌 克雷伯氏杆菌,肺结核菌和布鲁氏杆菌
and cultures for E.Coli,klebsiella,tb and brucella,
血检肠道病毒和腺病毒
blood tests for enteroviruses and adenoviruses.
希望针像他阴囊一样增大,这样就能找到了
Hopefully,the needles have grown as fast as his sack,and we can find it.
可以交给Chase和Cameron来做吗?
Can chase and cameron cover that?
介不介意我问问原因?
Mind if I ask why?
我想去全国骨髓库核查一下,是否有替代捐献者
I want to recheck the national marrow registry for an alternate donor.
以免我们错了?
In case we're wrong?
这已有先例
It's been known to happen.
好 去吧
Fine.Go.
大肠杆菌和肺结核菌都为阴性
negative for E.Coli and tb.
为什么House对Foreman这么好?
Why is house taking it easy on foreman?
他的确该喘口气
He deserves a break.
是啊 House懂得照顾别人的情绪
Yeah,house is all about giving breaks to people in need.
也不是克雷白氏杆菌
No on klebsiella.
今天是礼拜二
And it's tuesday.
跟Foreman和House都没关系,今天我该
It's got nothing to do with foreman or house.It's just--
提醒你我喜欢你
it's the day I remind you I like you,
希望我们能在一起
and I want us to be together.
谢谢
Thank you.
我都快忘了
I'd forgotten.
没有布鲁氏菌和两种病毒的抗体
No on brucella and both viral antibodies.
你真的打算每周二都这么做?
You're really gonna do this every tuesday?
你周二请假的话 我就改周三
You take the day off,I'll pick it upon wednesday.
会不会找错方向了?
What if we're looking for the wrong thing?
这些是唯一能导致阴囊肿胀的感染
These are the only infections that cause swollen testicles.
你能不能就现在说四遍,然后一个月都不来烦我?
Why don't you just say it four times now and leave me alone for a month?
会不会根本不是感染?
What if it's not an infection?
他的体温高得吓人,粘液都快从身体里流出来了
His temperature's through the roof,there's mucuspouring out of him.
我知道他有感染,如果不是感染直接导致阴囊问题
I know he has an infection,but what if it didn't directly cause the scrotum issue?
如果感染只是
What if it just.
引发了可致阴囊问题的病症
caused the thing that caused the scrotum issue?
ckmb(肌酸激酶同工酶)在升高
Ckmb is elevated.
一点 不能显示什么问题
Slightly.There's nothing wrong with--
显示了心脏受损
indicates cardiac injury.
我们把他关在那房间里,强力驱动他流流鼻涕的小感染
We stuck him in that room,put his stupid little runny nose infection into hyper drive.
会不会就奔向心脏了?
What if it went to his heart?
肺动脉瓣看上去没问题
pulmonary valve looks clean.
等等
wait.
停下
Stop.
二尖瓣那
Mitral valve.
有异常生长
There's a growth.
清除这个 得用一个月的抗生素
He'll need a month of antibiotics to clear that.
而他哥哥只有4天能活
His brother only has four days to live.
Matty的二尖瓣感染使他不能捐赠了
the infection in matty's mitral valve rules him out as a donor.
完美
This is perfect.
我们把感染赶到他的心脏去了
We drove the infection into his heart.
好吧 说完美太夸张了
Okay.Perfect is too strong a word.
但仍然非常 非常之好
But it's very,very good.
现在知道感染在哪儿
Now we know where the infection is.
只要移出那块瓣膜
All we gotta do is remove the valve,I.D.
确认感染 瞄准 破坏即可
The infection,target and destroy.
移除瓣膜?
remove the valve?
他用抗生素就能康复
He'll be fine on antibiotics.
根本没必要做需要开心的大手术
He doesn't need open heart surgery.
他哥哥死了 他会心碎的
He'll be heartbroken on account of his dead brother.
怎样他哥哥都活不成
either way,he's gota dead brother.
感染并不只限于瓣膜
The infection isn't just in the valve.
即使用药正确,也不可能及时清理整个系统
Even with targeted medication,there's no way we can clear his system in time.
没有必要
We don't have to.
只需要清理骨髓
We just have to clear his marrow.
手术之后 你们收获骨髓
After the surgery,you harvest the marrow,
泡制在针对性的抗生素中 慢炖 然后上菜
marinate it in the targeted antibiotic,simmer and serve.
可行
It could work.
这太疯狂了
It's insane.
总比死掉哥哥好
It is better than a dead brother.
我要去告诉Cuddy
I'm running this by cuddY.
好 去啊
Fine.Go.
其实 不如一起去
In fact,let's all go.
这个手术极其危险 生死攸关
This surgery is dangerous and life-altering.
绝没有考虑到病人的利益
And clearly not in the interest of our patient.
如果他爱他哥哥 算是考虑到了
It is if he likesh is brother.
- 我们有利益冲突,- 父母难道没有?
We have a conflict of interests.the parents don'T.
他们当然有
Of course they do.
他们不是第一次拿Matty的健康,来换他兄弟的命了
They already sacrificed matty's health to benefit his brother once.
他们只是加重了他的感冒
They made his cold worse.
感冒加重 损坏了他的心脏瓣膜
We screwed up his heart valve by making his cold wor.
对于这场辩论你有没什么好补充的?
Do you have anything to add to this debate?
Wilson正确 Foreman错误
Wilson's right,foreman's wrong,
你的上衣对坐办公室而言太暴露了点
and your shirt is way too revealing for the office.
想让我怎么做?
What do you want me to do?
打电话给儿童保护中心,让他们指派一个监护人给Matty
We should call child services and have them appointa guardian for matty.
不
No.
解释给家长 让他们选择
Go explain the choices to the parents.
小心别让House 威胁他们
And don't let housebully them.
House.
House
- 你真觉得我会听Foreman的?,- 不
- Did he really think I was gonna do that?,- I didn'T.
- 那你为什么让他,- 我让他松弛一下
- Then why did you let him,- tried to cut him some slack.
你人好好
Nice of you.
我觉得他得了yips,(运动员因紧张不安应变失常)
I think he's got the yips.
(棒球手)Steve Blass Scott Norwood,(高尔夫球手)David Duval都得了
Steve blass,scott norwood,david duval all got the yips.
伟大的运动员
Great athletes.
一朝失去自信 立马走下坡
Lost their confidence,and immediately started sucking.
而你在给他时间渡过这一关?
And you're.giving him timeto work through it?
四天 不行就滚蛋
Four days and then he's fired.
得了yips好不了
You don't get better from the yips.
心内直视手术?
Open-heart surgery?
想让两个孩子都活下来 这是唯一的方法
if you want both kids to live,it's the only choice.
因瓣膜被移除
due to the valve replacement,
Matty需要用血液稀释剂 预防梗塞
matty will have to be on blood thinners,to prevent potential clots.
- 一直持续多久?,- 一辈子
- For how long?,- Forever.
他将不能参加身体接触运动,以避免大出血
He couldn't participate in contact sports,because of the risk of hemorrhage.
骨髓库那怎样?
What about the marrow registry?
也许还有能配对的呢
Maybe they'll find a match.
也许他会骑着独角兽飞驰而来
Maybe they'll ride it here on a unicorn.
恐怕很难指望再找一个可行的捐赠者
I'm afraid finding a viable new donor isn't something we can realistically depend on.
要不弄残一个 要不就让另一个死？
Either we cripple one sonor kill the other.
他不能再打棒球
He won't be able to play baseball.
但并不代表就残了
But that doesn't make hima cripple.
我们该怎么办?
What should we do?
你们该保护一整个家庭
You should protect your family as a whole.
做手术吧
You should do the surgery.
这招太强了!
That was awesome!
闭嘴
Shut up.
我也该开始试着假装关心别人
I gotta start pretending to care.
我所做的正是Cuddy叫我们不要做的
I did exactly what cuddy told us not to do.
不不 你做的是她叫我不要做的
No,you didn'T.You did exactly what she told me not to do.
你完全清白无罪
You're completely in the clear.
开玩笑
You've gotta be kidding me.
你真难过起来了
You're actually upset.
你刚说的 正是你所相信的
You just said what you believed.
我也相信病人该自己选择
I also believe in patients making their own choices.
因为事情搞砸的时候 会少点内疚
Because it lessens your guilt if things go wrong.
那不是保护选择权
You're not protecting your choices.
是逃避自责
You're soothing your conscience.
照这逻辑 反社会者是世上,最好的病人权益倡导者
By that logic,a sociopath would make the best patient advocate in the world.
我脸红没?
Am I blushing?
- 准备好了?,- 是的
You ready?
谢谢
Thanks.
你为了我也会这么做
You'd do the same for me.
别担心
Don't worry.
你会没事的
You're gonna be fine.
我还来得及参加决赛么?
Think I'll be better in time to pitch in the playoffs?
要不下个赛季吧
Maybe next season.
我们应该告诉他的
We should have told him.
他爱他的哥哥
He loves his brother.
但他要是知道 这样做的后果--
But if he understood what we were asking of him--
他爱他哥哥 胜过棒球
he loves his brother more than he loves baseball.
你们做得对
You did the right thing.
不该将这样重大的决定交给他--
Putting any part of this decision on him--
对你们都太困难
it's impossible for you guys to deal with this.
十岁的孩子怎么能承受?
How's a ten-year-oldsupposed to do it?
导管就位
Canula in place.
缝线就位
Sutures are holding.
可以开始了
We're all set to go.
转换到体外循环
Switch him or to bypass.
手术没有做
I didn't do the surgery.
你叫醒我 告诉我你太懒了?
You woke me up to tell me that you're lazy.
我们切进去前做了一次活检
We biopsied a piece before we started cutting.
我很累 说重点
I'm tired.Get to the point.
没有换下瓣膜,因为那片生长只是纤维性组织
We didn't replace the valve because the growth was fibrous tissue.
没有感染
It wasn't infectious.
我们弄错了
We gotta be wrong about--
啊 上帝
oh,god.
怎么了?
What?
你知道Matty是什么问题了?
You know what'swrong with matty?
我觉得Hector他
I think hector'S.
自杀了
committed suicide.
你在说什么?
What are you talking about?
他吃了好些药片
He took some pills.
他还活着吗?
Is he alive?
他吃我快一半的储备粮
He ate half my stash.
怎么可能不--
Of course he's--
它正飘飘欲仙
He's stoned.
我就来
I'll be right in.
一路切进孩子的心脏
We cut all the way into this kid's heart,
得到的只是非感染性的破纤维组织
and all we got was this lousy,noninfectious fibrous tissue.
怎么会弄错的?
How did we miss this?
Matty发着烧
Matty had a fever.
抑制住他的免疫系统后 病情就加重
He got sicker whenwe suppressed his immune system.
这些都指着感染的存在
That all points to infection.
是啊是啊
Yeah,yeah,yeah.
不是我们的错
Not our fault.
纤维性组织
Fibrous tissue.
他好端端的心脏瓣膜怎么变成了软骨
Something is turning his healthy heart valve to gristle.
纤维性组织 扩大了的脾脏
fibrous tissue,enlarged spleen.
发烧 可能是自体免疫病
fever--could mean autoimmune.
自体免疫病不在骨髓中传播
Autoimmune diseases aren't passed along in bone marrow.
他还是能够捐赠
He can still donate.
确认一下 我做手术
We confirm,I do the surgery.
狼疮和白塞氏病可能性不大
Lupus and bechet's are our best bet.
做抗核抗体和过敏反应检测
Do an ana and a thergy test.
仍可能是感染
or it could be infection.
我的记忆力是大不如前
My memory's not what it used to be,
好像在8秒前排除了那个吧?
but didn't we just rule that out 8 seconds ago?
就算感染没有破坏他的瓣膜,也不能证明它不存在
Just because it's not what screwed up his valve doesn't mean it's not in his system.
我们要是猜对了 好处可大了
Uh-huh; and it has the obvious advantage of making us right all along.
猜错了 就一点坏处 哥哥死了
A little disadvantage of making big brother dead.
这就是你的论点?
That's your argument?
由结果好坏来判断?
Better outcome?
这说得通
It fits.
这家的孩子,一个白血病 一个自体免疫病
The family has one kid with leukemia and one with autoimmune.
太蹊跷了
Wouldn't stand next to them in a rainstorm.
这就是你的论点 悲惨得不可能发生?
That's your argument--it sucks for them?
也说得通 还救得了大的
It fits,and we can still help big brother.
全国骨髓库有一个六分之四配对的捐赠者
National marrow registry came up with a four out of six donor--
六分之六要好过六分之四吧
six out of six is two better than four out of six,right?
我是说 虽然2是个很小的数字
I mean,I know two is so small,
但代表的是 他会得移植物抗宿主病
but since it means that he's gonna get graft versus host disease,
骨髓攻击他的身体 痛苦地死去
the marrow will attack his body and he'll diea painful death.
找出是哪种自体免疫病
Find out what autoimmuneit is.
这个叫自体免疫病的,比起换心脏瓣膜是好还是坏?
Is this autoimmune better or worse than a new heart valve?
那取决于是哪种自体免疫病
It depends on which autoimmune it is.
但发现得早的话 大多都能控制
With early detection,most are manageable.
测试需要多长时间?
How long will the testing take?
这就是另一个好处
That's the other good thing about this.
感染有成千上万种 自体免疫病就只有那么几个
There's literally thousands of possible infections but only a handful of autoimmune conditions.
几小时内就会有答案的
We'll have the answerin a few hours.
医生?
hey,doctor?
这很糟糕吗?
Is this bad?
看不看电影?
Wanna catch a movie?
现在是凌晨一点
It's 1:00 in the morning.
我知道有个地方可以
I know a place.
虽然我不推荐你穿那鞋去
Although I wouldn't recommend wearing those shoes.
到底一只狗是怎么打开药瓶子的?
How,exactly,does a dog unscrew a bottle of pills?
脑筋急转弯?
Is that a riddle?
需要有与其它手指相对的拇指
It requires an opposable thumb.
我大概没有盖紧
I must have left it off.
丢在地上?
On the floor?
猜是他跳着从浴室台面拨弄下来的
I think he hopped upon the bathroom counter.
他有关节炎
He has arthritis.
这回不是我
Not me this time.
不 是你的臭狗!
No,it's your damn dog!
他见什么啃什么
He chews everything!
我的文件不见了
I was missing a file.
论文在他大便里
Found paper in his stool.
78年太阳唱片猫王的原版唱片 不见了
An original sun record78 elvis recording--gone.
哪有啃乙烯基的笨蛋?,(黑胶唱片的原材料)
Who the hell chews vinyl?
他是来寻仇的
He's vindictive.
他的命还很硬
And he's had a good,long life.
但他的末日来了
It's his time.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
我被Wilson的伪善绊倒了
I just tripped overwilson's self-righteousness.
有什么发现?
What do you got?
Matty检查都是阴性
Matty's negative for everything.
不是自体免疫病
It's not autoimmune.
只好再怀疑是感染
so we're back to infection.
Nick在迅速恶化
Nick's starting to deteriorate fast.
他的手臂上都是瘀青
He's got bruising all over his arms.
毛细血管在渗漏
Capillaries are leaking blood.
如果发生在大脑 他就死了
If it happens in his brain,he's dead.
只得用那个6个里4个匹配的捐献者了
We've got to go with the four out of six donor.
我难道没说清楚 4个比6个少?
Did I mention my concerns about four being less than six?
Wilson的第一任老婆犯了同样的错误
Wilson's first wife ignored a similar issue.
只不过在那时 是他们的婚姻丧了命
Of course,that time,it wasonly fatal to their marriage.
得随机检查Matty是哪种感染
It's either that or we start randomly testing matty for infections.
我知道你恨"随机"这个词
I know you hate the word random.
按首字母顺序来
Do it alphabetically.
不能做移植
We're not doing that damn transplant.
Foreman在哪儿?
Where's foreman?
找到一个捐献者
we found a donor.
不是完美匹配
It's not an ideal match.
不过6个里4个匹配 值得一试,(HLA测试6个白细胞抗原的相容程度)
But four out of six still gives nick a chance.
半匹配移植极其危险
a partial match transplant is extremely dangerous.
Foreman医生解释过了
Dr.Foreman explained.
他有没有提你们儿子会经历多大的痛苦?
He also explain what sort of pain your son will experience
- 如果他得了移植物抗宿主病?,- 是的
- if he gets graft versus host disease?,- Yes.
看来他的描述还不够鲜明
Apparently,he didn't explain it vividly enough.
让我来试一下
Let me give it a whack.
他也说 如果我们什么都不做
he also explained that if we did nothing,
Nick会颅内出血
nick could start bleeding into his brain.
Matty是完美的匹配
Matty is a perfect match.
请给我们多点时间来寻找
Just give us a little more time to figure out--
多久?
how much time?
House医生是最好的诊断专家
Dr.House is the best diagnostician--
要多久?
how much time?
不确定
I don't know.
Nick随时都回颅内出血
and nick can start bleeding into this brain without any warning.
但错配导致并发症的可能性
Yes,but the chances of complications from a mismatch--
我的儿子受够了
my boy shave suffered enough.
让Matty好起来
Get matty better.
让Nick接受新捐献者移植
And give nick the transplant from the new donor.
Foreman捅我们一刀
Foreman screwed us.
不 是你无能
No! You screwed us.
你能控制别人的决定 却不去做,有什么用?
What is the point in being able to control people if you won't actually do it?
就好像训练一条狗,却还纵容他尿在毯子上
It's like training a dog and then letting him go on your rug.Which,by the way.
一旦Foreman插手了 我就没办法
once foreman got his mitts on them,there was no way--
你没跟他们说清楚 风险和概率
you don't explain chances and probabilities.
你蒙骗了他们
You lie to them.
就算你告诉他们Foreman是低能
You tell them foreman's a moron--
现在看来都算不上是撒谎
which isn't even much of a lie right now.
你得去跟他谈谈
You've got to talk to him.
我不恼恨Foreman
I got no problem with what foreman did.
他暗地捅我们一刀,说不定还会要了那孩子的命
He undercut us and he may have cost that kid his life!
他认为正确的 他就去做
Well,he did what he thought was right.
而相反的 你这个软骨头
You,on the other hand,sucked out.
这么重要的抉择,你没勇气告诉他们该怎么做
When the decision really mattered,you didn't have the guts to tell them what to do.
如果孩子死了 Foreman有错,你这个懦夫也有错
If that kid dies,it's because foreman was wrong and because you're a coward.
哦 天!
Oh,goodness!
我忘了关门
I've left my door open.
可怜的狗狗肯定跑出去了,被汽车或卡车撞死
My poor dog must have run away and been hit by a car or truck.
被火车撞死
Or train.
被铁砧砸死
Or an anvil.
谢天谢地
Thank god.
你还在
you're still here.
他还在!
He's still here!
我的音响呢?
Where's my stereo?
感觉怎么样?
How you feeling?
有点痒
A little itchy.
多奇怪
It's weird,huh?
你们不知道我哪里出了问题
You still have no idea what's wrong with me,
可这些药物会让我好起来
but those meds will make me better.
我们给你用许多药物 能对抗多种感染
We put you on a variety of medications that'll fight all kinds of infections.
但是Nick
But nick.
你们很清楚他得了什么病
you know exactly what's wrong with him,
可他有可能还是会死
but maybe he's gonna die anyway.
希望新的骨髓能
Hopefully,the new marrow will--
我不能进去 是吗?
I can't go in there,can I?
你的感染对他致命
Your infection would kill him.
那我不能陪着他
So I won't be ableto be with him.
当他死时?
when he dies?
当他好起来时 你可以陪着他
You'll be able to be with him when he gets better.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
很痒
It really itches.
有人吗?
Hello?
为什么来这里?
Why am i meeting you here?
你要为我的新拐杖买单
You're paying for my new cane.
是你的狗
It was your dog.
就这样
So that's it.
你叫我懦夫 我们还做朋友
You call me a coward,life goes on.
显然
apparently.
你不是赴约了嘛
You showed up.
是我不对
I'm sorry.
算了
Okay.
你真可悲 我不是存心这么说
You're pathetiC.I didn't actually mean that.
- 你是有心的,- 不 我不是
- Yes,you did.,- No,I didn'T.
绝对的
To infinity.
你就是
Yes,you did.
你才可悲
You're pathetic.
什么时候?
When?
检测结果怎么样?
What did the lab say?
你为什么不能像别的瘸子,在一家医疗器械店买拐杖?
Why don't you buy your cane in a medical supply store like a normal cripple?
那里好货色少
Fewer bitchin' choices.
行
Okay.
最好的放在哪里?
What do you got in bitchin'?
在那里
Right this way.
Cameron打来的
That was cameron.
病得不太重的孩子垂危了
The kid that wasn't all that sick is now all that sick.
他耳内出血
He's bleeding out of his ears.
血球计数?
blood counts?
下降
Down.
血涂片的红细胞碎片呢?
schistocyteson the smear?
他的身体不能制造新的血细胞
His body's not making new blood cells.
他的骨髓不行了
His bone marrow's crashing.
这是畅销产品
This is one of our top sellers.
这在敬老院里显得太玛瑞莲·曼森了,(Marilyn Manson:妖异鬼魅的金属乐团)
It's a little too marilyn manson in a retirement home.
药物抑制了他骨髓的功能
Meds are suppressing his bone marrow.
也许是感染导致的
Or the infection's doing it.
很有型
Very cooL.
公牛阳具包裹在金属杆外
Genuine bull penis stretched over a metal rod.
阳具拐杖是谋杀
Penis canes are murder.
最里面那根给我瞧瞧
Let me see the one on the end.
你选对了
You got it.
得停了Matty的药
You need to stopmatty's meds.
如果功能反弹 说明是药物
The marrow rebounds,it's the meds.
如果没有 则是感染
If it doesn't,it's an infection.
如果是感染呢?
And if it's the infection?
那就说不定哪个孩子会死了
Maybe I was wrong about which kid's gonna die.
拉风
Bitchin'.
火焰
Flames.
让我走得更快了
Makes it look like I'm going fast.
垂死的孩子怎么样了?
Now,how's our dying kid?
Nick的脚和腿长满了水泡
Nick's developed blisters all over his feet and legs.
已经是四级移植物抗宿主病
He's got grade four graft versus host.
加大他甲基强的松的量,(用于器官移植排异反应)
Increase his dosage of methylprednisolone.
加了 没有效果
Already did.It's not working.
内疚了?
Feeling guilty?
我没做错
I did the right ing.
自我安慰
Always a comfort.
另一个孩子的情况呢?
Okay,what's the other kid's status?
Nick讨论完了?
We're done with nick?
上帝放弃了Nick
God is done with nick.
知道他的病情
We know what he has.
知道该怎么治
We know how to treat it.
治了 没起效
We're doing it.It's not working.
能活下去的人才有生命
Life is for the living.
Matty的药停了几个小时
matty's been off his meds for a few hours,
血球计数没起色
but his blood count's still tanking.
说明不是药物惹的祸
It means the meds aren't to blame.
是感染
It's the infection.
如果不控制住 他的血液会变成清水
If we don't get this under control,his blood will literally turn into water.
血液培养没有发现
Cultures still aren't growing anything.
怎么会
Why not?
因为你做了你觉得对的事
Because you did the right thing.
说服父母治疗孩子
Convinced the parents to treat the kid.
你做的只不过是拔了地上的野草
All you did was yank the weed out of the ground.
根还在扼杀美丽的草坪
It's roots are still killing your beautiful lawn.
只不过我们看不见
We just can't see it.
看不见就不知道是什么
And if we can't see it,we don't know what it is.
不知道是什么 就对付不了
And if we don't know what it is,we can't kill it.
得等它再长出来
You gotta wait for itto grow back again.
可他的土壤贫瘠
Now his soil is arid.
他们兄弟俩都会死
So he and his brother will be dead by the time--
如果蒲公英长在肥沃的土壤
what if the dandelion was in fertile soil?
把Matty身上的野草根,种到Nick身上
What if we take the roots from matty and put them in nick?
把那孩子当作培养皿
Turn the kid into a petri dish?
比培养皿更好
Only better.
培养皿不会叫疼
A petri dish can't tell you when it hurts.
你想把感染给他哥哥?
You want to give him his brother's infection?
自从他打喷嚏来,我们千方百计避免的事?
The very thing we've been trying to avoid since the brother sneezed?
白血病孩没有抵抗力
Leukemia kid's got no defenses.
所以他要死了
Which is why he'll die.
在他死前 感染会迅速蔓延
But before he does,the infection will spread,fast.
来得及让我们发现它是什么
Fast enough to tell us what it is.
来得及救他弟弟
In time to save his brother.
还有别的法子吗?
Do you see any other way?
感染在屠戮Matty的骨髓
the infection is decimating matty's bone marrow.
但
But.
如果把Matty的骨髓给Nick
if we give that marrow to nick,
他的症状能帮助我们诊断Matty
his symptoms could let us diagnose matty.
但会杀了Nick
But it'll kill nick.
是的
Yes.
你是说 我们该用一命换一命?
You're-- you're saying we should,kill one son to save the other?
Nick治不好了
Nick is gonna die either way.
不许这么说!
you don't know that!
他现在是很痛苦 但
I mean,he's in pain right now,but--
药物对Nick的移植物抗宿主病无效
nick's graft versus host is not responding to medication.
会有起色的
It can change.
也许 他 他能挺过来
May--maybe he'll--he'll rally.
我的Nick从不服输
Hey,my nick is a fighter.
阳光笑容和正面形象,并不能让他免于排异反应
graft versus host is not gonna go away because of nick's sunny smile and positive outlook.
Nick挺过了三次白血病复发
Nick has survived three reoccurrences of his leukemia.
他的全身都被破坏了一遍
He's being torn apart from the inside out.
他会越来越痛苦 直至死亡
His pain's gonna get worse and worse until he dies.
现在只是无谓的拖延
You're just dragging it out.
你只有两个选择
You have only one decision to make--
死一个儿子还是两个
to leave here with one dead son or two.
告诉他们
Tell them.
你应该让我们做这个
You should let us do this.
不
No.
我们不会放弃Nick
We're not giving upon nick.
不会
Not!
显然他们一个儿子都不想要了
patients' parents apparently don't want to be parents anymore.
你平时就够奸猾的
You're a sneaky bastard.
有什么主意吗?
Any ideashow we get around this?
法庭强制?
Court order?
这根本算不上奸滑
That's hardly sneaky.
我们可以救Matty
We can still save matty.
多做些化验
Run more tests.
找到破坏骨髓的病原
Find out what infection is destroying his marrow.
一万种感染
10,000 possible infections.
每种至少20分钟
At least 20 minutes per test.
差不多要8年做完
Take you approximately eight years.
实际上只要4个月,即使我查到最后一项化验才中
Actually,four months,assuming the last one I test is the right one.
如果第一项就中 只要20分钟
If it's the first,it'll take me approximately 20 minutes.
他是对的
he's right.
可以一试
It's worth a shot.
他没胆子了
He's timid.
盲目检查救不了这孩子
Testing blindly is not gonna save this kid.
在这里站着就可以了?
But standing around here will.
他是真的疼
Wow,he sure is hurting.
护士说止疼药已经用到最大剂量
Nurses say he maxed out on his pain meds.
如果每次听到这句话,我都能得到一个硬币...
If I had a nickel for every time I heard that.
药房在一楼
pharmacy's on the ground floor.
我给你去拿止疼药
I'm gonna go get you some more pain medication,okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
没用的
It's not gonna help.
你会死的
You're dying.
无法挽回了
Nothing's gonna change that.
药只能让你死得好过些
Drugs'll just make you go easier.
我知道
I know.
人世间的14年
14 years on the planet.
多数在痛苦中渡过
Most of them spent suffering.
甚至没尝过
Dying before you even got to.
驾车 解胸罩 喝啤酒
drive a car,take off a girl's bra,drink a beer.
你没做过的事太多了
Believe me,there's plenty you haven't done.
美好的事
Really good stuff.
你一定不相信有-
Must make it hard to believe in.
上帝
god or.
不信有公平 不信未来
fairness and a larger purpose.
但你的生命并非毫无意义
But your life doesn't have to be meaningless.
你可以救你弟弟
You can save your brother.
怎么救
How?
未发现巨细胞病毒
negative for cmv.
没有阿米巴虫
negative for amoebas.
House说你没胆
House called you timid.
他说我比这狠多了
He's called me a lot worse.
他才不在乎狠不狠
To him,there is nothing worse.
他会开除你
He's gonna fire you.
即使我们检查一百项
Even if we runa hundred tests,
也只有1%的几率救活他
that only gives us a 1% chance of saving these kids.
总比零好
Better than zero.
你不怕被解雇?
You don't care if you get fired?
不知道 一定有办法 让死亡低于99%
I don't know,there's got to be a way to better our odds from 99% chance of death.
你得知道
You gotta know.
肯定不是来自食物 因为家人都健康
It's not food-borne,because no one else in the family is sick.
到底在不在意被解雇
Either you care about your job or you don'T.
只有Matty从那个机井里喝过水
Matty's the only one who drank from that water pump in the backyard,
已经排除了假单胞菌和霍乱
but we eliminated pseudomonas and cholera.
如果你在意 就应努力保住工作
If you care,you fight to keep it.
不在意就干脆辞职
If you don't,you quit.
我以为他们住在郊区
I thought they lived in the suburbs.
就是的 怎么了?
They do.Why?
他家有机井?
They've got a water pump?
求你了 我愿意
plse,I wanna do it.
不 Nicky
no,nicky.
这不是你该做的决定
It's not your decision.
我要死了
I'm dyinG.
这是无法改变的
There's nothing that's gonna change that.
别这么说
Don't say that,okay?
绝不能放弃
You can't give up.
让我走吧, 爸爸
It's time for me to go,dad.
是时候让我走了
You gotta let me go.
不
No.
儿子
Please,son.
我不能
I can'T.
不能!
I can't!
让我为Matty做一件事
Let me do it for matty.
让我为你们做一件事
Let me do it for you guys.
让他陪伴你们
so you won't be alone.
你下决心了吗?
Are you sure?
没
no.
他下了
But he is.
把Nick推回无菌房
get nick back to the clean room.
家人同意感染他
The parents agreed to infect him.
我知道Matty的病因了
We figured out what's wrong with matty--
组织胞浆菌病
histoplasmosis.
这是什么东西 他怎么会...
well,what is that? I mean,why did it--
真菌感染
fungal infection.
在鸡粪里生长
Grows in chicken feces.
投球区的土应该是来自鸡舍的
The dirt that matty used to build his pitcher's mound must have sat under a chicken coop.
你们整个社区都是建在农场上
Your whole neighborhood was built on top of farmland.
早先我们没有检查这项 因为...
We didn't test for it earlier because we--
能治好吗?
can you fix him?
全面施用两性霉素 他会好的
Full course of amphotericin,and he should be fine.
那Nick呢
And nick?
能不能先治好Matty 然后-
I mean,can you clean matty's marrow,um,
就像你们之前说的 只不过加快速度
just like you were talking about doing it,but do it fast and.
把骨髓给Nick
and get it into nick?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
Matty之所以病得这么重,是因为骨髓受到感染
The reason matty is so sick is because the infection's attacking his marrow.
这时候取骨髓 Matty可能有危险
He doesn't have enough left to safely take from him and give to his brother.
我会好起来?
I'm going to get better now?
就这样
That's it?
是这样
That's it.
Nick怎么办?
And what about nick?
你哥哥甘冒生命危险救你
Your brother was willing to risk his life to save you.
你愿意为他这样做吗?
Are you willing to do that for him?
不能打麻药
I can't sedate you.
你太虚弱
You're too sick.
求求你住手
Please,please stoP.
求求你
Please,please.
已经抽完了吧
You're done,right?
对不起
Sorry.
还要很多
I need a lot more.
停下
No.Stop!
停
Stop!
很难招架那对父母吧?
How much heat are you taking from the parents?
他们正在冷静
They're calming down.
大概是因为两个儿子都活着,醒了而且可以进食
I think it has something to do with both their kids being alive,awake,and eating.
骨髓移植有效果
The marrow transplant took.
欢迎回来 Foreman
Welcome back,foreman.
你应该和他谈谈
You should talk to him.
告诉他我为他骄傲?
And tell him how proud I am?
如果你认为他很丢脸,也可以跟他说
Hey,if you're ashamed of him,you can tell him that.
跟有感情的人 才谈得上骄傲还是丢脸,对雇员用不着
Pride and shame only apply to people we have a vested interest in,not employees.
你要跟人相处多久才能感觉亲如一家?
How many hours a day do you have to spend with someone before they're basically family?
说得好
Good point.
不过首先 我要跟Cameron和Chase,说说他俩冒犯上帝的事
But first,I gotta tell cameron and chase that they're violating god's will.
我只是希望你跟他像成人般地谈谈,让他知道
I'm just asking you to have an adult conversation to let him know--
让他知道他做得对?
he did a good job?
他知道的
He knows it.
成人不需要成人对话
Adults don't need adult conversations.
就好像我不需要听你废话
Just like I don't need this conversation.
你干掉Hector没有?
Have you killed hector yet?
显然还没
Obviously not.
他很安静
He's quiet.He's--
那是我的听诊器?
is that my stethoscope?
狗狗坏!
Bad dog!
听我说
Listen.
Bonnie加入了业主会 经过一番斗争
bonnie joinedher home owners association and staged a coup.
现在允许养宠物了
Pets are now allowed.
如果你想留着狗 她可以再养一条
If you want to keep him,she wants a new puppy anyway.
她会理解的
She'll understand.
我怎么会想留着他?
Why would I wantto keep him?
你肯定?
You're sure.
走了 小伙子
Come on,boy.
以下歌曲"Ain't No Reason",演唱: Brett Dennen
"Ain't No Reason"
意外
accidents happen.
糖?
candy?
好孩子
good boy.
你做得对
you did good.
我做了你会做的事
I did what you would have.
那么
Well.
也许我有偏见 但是-
maybe I'm biased,but--
我折磨那个小孩
I tortured the kid.
因为你知道那样是对
Because you knew it was right.
那是为了救他哥哥
You knew you were saving his brother.
我知道
I know.
我宁愿不知道
I don't like that I know.
我不喜欢听着小孩惨叫
I hate that I can listen to a kid screaming in pain
却绝不停下片刻质疑自己是否正确
and not even take a moment to question whether I'm doing the right thing.
为了成为和你一样的医生
I hate that in order to be like you as a doctor,
我只能先学你的为人
I have to be like you as a human being.
我讨厌变成你
I don't want to turn into you.
你没有变成我
You're not.
你从8岁起就是我了
You've been like me since you were eight years old.
你会比我救更多的人
You'll save more people than I will.
但我满足于少害死人
But I'll settle for killing less.
就当我的辞职报告吧
Consider this my two weeks' notice.